e-mudhra.com 2019-03-28

# Privacy Policy | eMudhra

Last updated: Oct 26th, 2018

* * *

Introduction  
We value the trust you place in eMudhra. eMudhra consists of eMudhra Limited, eMudhra Inc, eMudhra Pte Ltd, eMudhra DMCC and other subsidiaries and affiliates. Your privacy is extremely important to us. We won't ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.

By using our Website, you consent to the collection and use of this information by our Website as described in this privacy policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

Our privacy policy describes the ways in which eMudhra collects, stores, uses, shares and protects your personal information and it is important for you to review this privacy policy. By "personal information" we mean information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person.

We do not consider anonymized information to constitute personal information, as it cannot be used to identify a specific person. We collect personal information from you when you use eMudhra products and/or services and/or its related sub-domains, mobile applications, sites, services and tools or when you telephone or email our support team or chat with them.

By providing us with your personal information you expressly consent to us processing your personal information in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy.

We are sensitive to privacy issues and have established this policy so that you can understand the care with which we intend to treat your Personal Information. This privacy policy should be read in conjunction with our Terms of Service.

If you or your organization has an individual agreement with us, that agreement may have privacy terms that also apply to the information you provide to us under that agreement. Please review the terms in that agreement because they may be different or more restrictive than the terms in this Privacy Policy.

This privacy policy does not apply to any third party websites and apps that you may use.

Gathering of your personal information  
To provide, improve and support our services, we gather information about visitors to our sites, users of our products and/or services, the devices they use and their locations. These information are either directly collected from you when you fill out the forms or automatically when you use our site or through other sources, such as, if we purchase a list of contact information of people who may be interested in our services.

You provide information about yourself when you register or login into your account, purchase products and/or services, create or edit your user profile, start, sign electronic documents, contact our support, comment on our blogs or in community forums or and/or use our application.

You also provide us information about others when you use parts of our products and/or services such as start or participate in an electronic transaction, add others as member of an existing account or for any transaction, leave comments, refer friends and/or run data analytics using our platforms.

In this connection, you have the choice to provide whatever information you feel appropriate. However, not providing certain information may restrict your ability to use our sites partially or fully.

AUTOMATIC COLLECTION OF DATA  
The information we automatically collect includes, Device, Usage Information, and Transactional Data. We collect information about how you use our Services and the computers or other devices, such as mobile phones or tablets, you use to access our Services.

Some examples include, IP address, geolocation information that you allow our apps to access (usually from your mobile device), Unique device identifiers and device attributes, like operating system and browser type, other data such as web log data, referring and exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages and content viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time you used our Services, the frequency of your use of our Services, error logs, and other similar information, Transactional data (non-content data about electronic transactions you start, review, or sign), such as: names and email addresses of parties to a document or transaction, document or transaction subject, history of actions that individuals take on a document or transaction (e.g. review, sign) and information about those individuals or their devices, such as name, email address, IP address, and authentication methods and certificate profiles.

COOKIES AND RELATED TECHNOLOGY  
Like many websites, we use 'cookie' technology (small computer files placed on your computer's hard drive) and other technologies such as web beacons, local shared objects, and tracking pixels to store or collect information. When you go to particular website pages on the Site, the cookie identifies your browser with a unique, random number and can store your preferences, username and help tailor advertisements.

The cookies we use do not reveal any personal information about you. Cookies help us improve your experience of the Site and also help us understand which parts of the Site are most popular. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although doing so may interfere with your use of the Site.

For more information on usage of Cookies, please refer our section on Cookie Policy The above privacy policy relating to cookies covers the use of cookies by eMudhra and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers on our website.

ANALYTICS  
We use services like Google Analytics. They use Cookies to gather website usage data and gather behavior of people that use our Services, such as the pages they visit, duration of visit and the referral pages before visiting an eMudhra website or landing pages within eMudhra website etc.

ADVERTISING  
Ads for Other Products & Services. Third parties whose products or services are marketed on our Product and/or Services may place or read from Cookies on your computer or other device to collect information. They do this to (i) tailor and serve advertising based on behavioral information like past visits to our Services and other sites; and (ii) report the number of ads served and the responses to those ads;

Ads for our Products and Services. We may also use services, like Google, to serve tailored ads about our products and Services to you on our Services and elsewhere. We allow these third parties to use and access their own cookies on your computer or other device(s) you use to access our Services. We do not have access to these cookies or related technologies, and this Privacy Policy does not govern the use of those cookies and related technologies.

INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM OTHER SOURCES  
We may collect information about you from other sources which include partners, affiliates, marketers, researchers and others where they are legally allowed to share information with us. We may also collect information about from other customers when they include you as part of any signing or analytics workflow performed through our platforms.

COMBINING INFORMATION  
We may combine information received from multiple sources and use it as described in the privacy policy

GDPR  
When our customers use our products or services, we process and store certain information on their behalf as a "Data Processor" in accordance with their instruction. In those instances, the customer is the "Data Controller" and is responsible for most aspects of processing the information. In such circumstances, we request you to contact the relevant customer for any questions relating to the way in which such is processed.

How do we use information gathered?

We use the gathered information to provide our services, to fix and improve upon them, to develop new services and to market eMudhra's products and/or services.

In particular, such usage of gathered information may be for the following purposes

  * To manage eMudhra's signing and analytics platforms including support systems and security, develop new features, enhancements and introduce changes in our products and/or services
  * To prevent or mitigate fraud, unauthorized access and other wrongful behavior on our platforms
  * To meet the legal and compliance requirements relating to our products/service offerings
  * To fix problems encountered by customers relating to our products and/or services
  * To market features, products, services, send information about contests or special events, deliver advertising and tailored content or send you information about third party products and/or services, through email, phone or chat
  * To send you information about our relationship, including purchases, renewals and other events, provide you with products and/or services you request and collect payments
  * To store and review information about how any transaction moved through our platform and the users and devices that was used to access those transactions/information.

We may combine and aggregate the information we collect and do analysis and research on that information. This may be used for product and/or service enhancements or marketing. This privacy policy does not apply to such aggregated information.

LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR INFORMATION UNDER GDPR  
We collect or use the information from you, with your consent, for performing a contract with you, providing our products and/or service offerings for your use, and for protecting our legitimate interest. Further, in several situations we may also have legal obligation to collect or retain personal information and may need personal information to protect your interest or those of other persons.

Some examples include

  * Your personal information is needed to provide relevant services to you
  * To comply with regulations, we need to store data that is relating to your digital certificate or digital signature
  * To send emails for marketing purposes and for notifications, we use your names and email addresses. We do this with your consent which you can revoke at any time.

If you have any questions relating to this, you may contact Data Protection Officer at privacy@emudhra.com

How do we share information gathered?  
We share your information with service providers who support us in offering our services. These service providers include technology, cloud hosting, email systems, marketing, advertising, authentication, bill collection, fraud detection, payment processors and customer support partners. Our service providers are not permitted to use the information shared for their own purposes. When you allow others to access, use, or edit content in your account, we share that content with them.

We also share your information with other companies which are in the common ownership or control with eMudhra. These companies may use the information as per this privacy policy for all the purposes for which eMudhra can use the information.

We may also share your information to follow applicable law or to respond to legal processes and to protect legal rights of third parties including our employees, users or the public.

We may also share your information during a corporate transaction like a merger or sale of our assets.

With your consent, we may also share information about you for any other purpose or in any other manner for which you have given consent.

When you comment on our blogs or community forums, this information may also be read, collected and used by others.

Your profile information could be accessed by other users in our platforms unless you make this information private by choosing appropriate account settings.

If your account is created under any organization, that organization may be able to access information relating to your account and modify information or take certain actions which may affect your account.

We do not sell, rent or share your information except as described in this privacy policy.

How long do we retain your information?  
eMudhra may retain the information collected from you as described in this privacy policy for as long as you use our services or as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which it was collected or as necessary to resolve any disputes, establish legal defences, conduct audits, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements and to comply with applicable laws.

Your Choices  
While some of the information may be mandatory, some other information may be optional. Without providing the mandatory information, you may not be use our product/services. You can choose not to provide certain optional information. However this may limit your ability whole or part of the services.

Further, at any time you will have the option to edit the information you have provided and also to change certain settings, wherever it is offered by us, so as to restrict certain functions such as marketing messages, non-sharing of the profile.

In some cases, the option to edit information and option to change settings such as Cookies, location information etc may be offered respective platforms such as Browsers, Mobile Devices which are not the under of eMudhra.

Further at any time you can close your account with eMudhra.

We are committed to resolving valid complaints about your privacy and our collection and use of your personal data. For questions, please contact us at privacy@emudhra.com

Children's Privacy  
Our Services are not designed for and are not marketed to people under the age of 18 ("minors"). We do not knowingly collect or ask for information from minors. We do not knowingly allow minors to use our Services. If you are a minor, please do not use our Services or send us your information. We delete information that we learn is collected from a minor without verified parental consent.

GDPR Rights  
If you are established in European Union, you may have additional rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation. To protect your rights, eMudhra may execute standard contractual clauses approved by European Commission for your benefit (consumer standard contractual clauses) in order to ensure adequate protection for the personal data in accordance with the requirements of the EU General Data Protection Regulation.

If you wish to exercise your rights, please contact privacy@emudhra.com

Protecting your personal information  
We hold your personal information on secure servers. By providing us with personal information, you consent to the transfer of your personal information to, and its storage on, our secure servers. We take every precaution to safeguard all your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. However, the Internet is not a secure medium and we cannot guarantee absolute privacy or confidentiality of your personal information.

You must enter your username and password each time you want to access your account or make transactions on the Site.

Choose your password carefully using unique numbers, letters and special characters. Never share your username and password with anyone.

If you are concerned that your password has been compromised, please contact our customer support team immediately and ensure you change your password by logging onto the User settings section of the Site.

Changes to Our Privacy Statement  
From time to time we may revise this privacy policy. It is your obligation that you visit the website regularly and make yourself aware of any changes we make to this privacy policy, including a material change in the way we use your personal information and it will be deemed to be notified to and read by you on your using the Website once we post the same on our Website since the same is available.

Security Measures  
At eMudhra, we use the industry-standard Secured Socket Layer (SSL) protocol which provides data encryption, message integrity, and server authentication when your data is sent to us. When you see a small lock at the bottom right or left corner of your browser window, you know your data is being encrypted for transmission. All information (including email address) you enter while using eMudhra sites and platforms are used to provide the services requested by you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. Access to (and the use thereof) personally identifiable customer information is restricted to authorized personnel as dictated by service, support, and / or fulfillment requirements.

Service Alerts and Critical Notices  
Although we respect and honor your privacy preferences, eMudhra shall maintain the right to contact you when it is required to make you aware of changes that may impact your ability to use eMudhra's products and services.
